Vandish Gandhi

+61 450602494 vandish009@hotmail.com

Profile

I am an experienced lead frontend developer who is strongly focused on the javascript(primarily frontend) ecosystem. I have React, Angular, Vue, Vanilla JS implemented components and Ember's commercial experience of 6+ years. I am ICAgile certified for agile fundamental practices and a team player ranging from my primary specialisation on the front-end to API engineering and infrastructure setup for cross platform apps. In conjunction with proven people/(pro)developers management skills, I host a strong project, resource and development management skills.

Education

Master of Business (Information Systems & ERP) - Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia (2013) Bachelor of Computer Application - Gujarat University, India (2011)

Industry Experience

Senior Frontend Consultant for ARQ - Contract (June 2020 - Present)

Responsible for:

- Current client Telstra
- Developing front matter for Telstra's main website
- Create and architect reusable components for authors and producers in AEM
- Maintaining CI and Build pipeline
- Facilitating solution planning for UX'ers and designers
- Mentoring and training other developers, onshore and offshore

Application Stack:

Front end: HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Styled Components

Backend: AEM

Bundling tools: Webpack, Rollup

Testing: DOM Testing Library, React Testing Library, Browserstack

Devops: Docker, Bamboo, AWS Fargate, AMP Adobe AEM

Analytics: New Relic

Frontend Lead for Adslot (November 2018 – June 2020)

Responsible for:

- Contributing to front-end decision-making and architecture
- Maintaining team focus on reusable code, patterns and libraries
- Optimising application for maximum performance, maintainability and Scalability
- Maintaining open-source UI pattern libraries in React
- Collaborating and communicating with Front-End/Full-Stack Developers and stakeholders

- Mentoring, training and organising other developers with workshops
- Conducting thorough and constructive code-reviews and unit-tests
- Identifying new technology trends to implement in code base
- Contributing with product team in estimating solution delivery timeline
- Conducting regular 1:1 with direct reports and looking after their skill growth

Direct Reports: 3 Frontend devs

Application Stack:

Front end: React, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Styled Components, Angular Front end state management: Redux and React Context API

Backend: Node.js

Bundling tools: Webpack, Rollup

Testing: Jest, Enzyme, Puppetier, Selinium

Devops: Jenkins, Travis CI, AWS

Analytics: Amplitude

Project Management Tools: Jira, Confluence

Other: GraphQL, Apollo Server

Senior/Lead Frontend Developer for Telstra (August 2017 – November 2018)

Project: Prepaid Activation (https://telstra.com.au/prepaidactivation)

Responsible for:

- Leading and maintaining frontend applications for prepaid activation.
- Creating reusable AEM components for authoring and hosting SPA on AEM 6.3
- Driving the UX to make sure the application is responsive on web development, cross-browser and platform agnostic.
- Mentoring offshore developers in React development and ensure smooth bi-weekly development cycle with efficient source control management.
- Analysing business requirements to propose software design approach

Direct Reports: 4 fullstack, 1 frontend

Application Stack:

Front end: React with Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Less, Bootstrap, JQuery and DOM api. Project Management Tools: Atlassian Jira, Confluence & Microsoft Sharepoint

Source Control: Atlassian Sourcetree/Bitbucket, Git

Frontend Developer for ERM Power Ltd. (June 2016 – August 2017)

Project: Customer Portal (https://myportal.ermpower.com.au)

Responsible for:

- Developing user interface and engineering user experience for customer portal built on EmberJS
- Analysing business requirements to propose software design approach
- Driving the customer facing look and feel of ERM Web user interfaces

Application Stack:

Front end: Ember.js, HTML5, CSS3, Saas, Bootstrap

Backend: ASP.NET MVC, C#

Software Developer for University of Technology (June 2015 – June 2016) Project: Farm management dashboard

Responsible for:

- Developing, maintaining and cross platform testing frontend application build on Angular 1.5.
- Integrating Bootstrap, Angular Material and Foundation frameworks to enhance look and feel of web application as required.

Software Developer for Bombardier Transportation (June 2014- June 2015) Project: QNGR (Queensland New Generation Rolling stock)

Responsible for:

• Full Stack development using MVC architecture in PHP, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Ajax and jQuery using MySQL as a backend database

Programming Intern for Cosmic Infocom, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India (2010-2011) Responsible for:

• Coding firmware to communicate with PRI interface for call conferencing purposes.

Technical Skills

Java scripting Framework : React, Angular, Ember, Vanilla js, jQuery, backbone

Analytics : Adobe Analytics, New Relic

Content Management : AEM, WordPress

Web Designing : HTML5, Bootstrap, CSS, SaaS and Less, styled components

Automated Testing : Selenium, Jasmine, Karma, Jest, Mocha (Expert)

Reporting Tools : Omniture, Power BI

Computer Programming : C, C++, Bash Scripting (Linux), COBOL, Pascal

Server Side Programming : ASP.Net,PHP,Node.js, Python,C#,VBA(Event driven)

Data Formats : XML, JSON

ERP System : SAP

Project Management tool : Microsoft Project, Atlassian Jira Web Services : REST, SOAP (Working Knowledge)

RDBMS : MYSQL, Postgres SQL

NoSQL : Mongo DB

Source Control Systems : GIT, Github, Sourcetree (GUI), Github GUI

Web server Framework : Apache Xampp, IIS, Hadoop (conceptual understanding)

Certification

• ICAgile. Certification: Agile professional

- Authority: Australian Computer society. Certification: Analyst Programmer.
- Authority: SAP University Alliance & Victoria University.

Hobbies and Interest

Photography, snooker and travelling.